Joshua Walters

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/joshuawalters1991/

PROFILE

I am a junior full-stack developer in-training, having previously worked in the field of Marketing and Communications.

I have always had an interest in becoming a developer, and had looked to incorporate aspects of it into my previous career but feared my chance to do it professionally had passed me by. Following the recent birth of my first child, this provided the final impetus and I decided to take the leap and commit myself full-time to learning and pursuing a career as a developer.

I have now undertaken an intensive, 13-week coding bootcamp with Northcoders and am ready to start my career as a full-stack developer.

I was drawn to coding as I enjoy the problem-solving and collaborative working aspects, and look forward to joining a new team and collaborate on exciting, rewarding and challenging projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: Javacript, HTML/CSS, JSX
- Fundamentals: Test Driven Development, Pair Programming, Object Orientated Programming,
- Web Frameworks/libraries: Express, React, React Native
- **Runtime environments**: node.js
- **Databases**: PostgreSQL, SQL, Firestore (Firebase)
- Testing Suites: Jest
- CI/CD: Heroku

EDUCATION

BA (Hons) Journalism, City University London 09/2011 - 07/2014 2:1

A-Levels, QEGS Wakefield

2003 - 2010

Design & Technology, Mathematics, Politics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Student Software Developer, *Northcoders*

01/2022 - 04/2022 | Leeds

Northcoders is a multi-award winning organisation with a prestigious coding bootcamp.

I undertook an intensive 13-week course with them to learn the skills required to become a full-stack developer. I gained in-depth knowledge in backend and frontend development, and worked on a number of projects to practice and hone these skills.

From this I have produced an extensive portfolio. This can be viewed in full on my **Github** \mathscr{D} , and key parts can be accessed directly below:

- Backend Project News API: A RESTful, redditstyle API, creating endpoints with Express that access a PSQL database for CRUD operations. The project was built using Test Driven Development, with Supertest and Jest. View here ∂
- **Frontend Project / readdit:** Front End for News API, developed as a React web-app, using Axios to access API endpoints. View here ∂
- Final Project: Planet Scran It: A React Native application with a Firebase Backend. Planet Scran It is a family meal planner app with a range of functionality to create a custom menu and shopping list from a user's inputs. **View here** *⊗*

CRM & Conversion Co-ordinator,

Leeds Conservatoire

01/2017 – 12/2021 | Leeds

Managed CRM system and large communication campaigns. Implemented new CRM system, working as project manager from inception to delivery with internal and external teams. I also undertook further roles during my employment.

Marketing Assistant, University of Huddersfield 03/2016 - 01/2017 | Huddersfield Performing a number of marketing and communications tasks. Created database from scratch to oversee stock of marketing materials for promotional events.